Midhun Sarath Yellinedi

Phone: +1 (209)-319-6362 E-Mail: y.midhunsarath@gmail.com

Profile Summary

Having 10 years of experience as an IT professional in cloud technology, AWS, AZURE & Google cloud Platform and its multiple services. Also have experience with terraform on automation of creating AWS, AZURE and GCP resources. Well versed with understanding the client requirements and providing the best solution and deploying it, currently working as **Senior Systems** Operations Engineer at Wells Fargo.

Experience

Client: Wells Fargo May 2018 – Till Date

Project Name: Commercial and Corporate & Investment Banking Technology

Has been part of multiple projects during the tenure under this LOB, which provided me immense scope to explore and gain knowledge over several applications and work in different roles to enhance my skills in different technical areas.

Responsibilities:

- Extensive experience in setting up Amazon **EC2** instances, worked closely with infrastructure teams to Troubleshoot complex issues and setting up security groups.
- Experience on **Auto Scaling**, **ELB** Application Load Balancer, classic load balancer. Hands on experience on Configuring AMIs (Amazon Machine Image).
- Extensive experience in creating **S3 Bucket** in AWS and managing bucket policies and permissions. Worked on creating life cycle rules to move data from one storage class to another storage class.
- Hands on experience with data pipeline, **Athena**.
- Hands on experience with **Snowball** installation as well as moving the data from On-Premises to the Snowball Device.
- Experienced in Creating **IAM** user (**AWS** console access, Programmatic access), groups, Policies, roles and attaching specific policy to the user.
- Hands on experience in creating KMS Key to encrypt EBS Volumes.
- Experienced in configuring **Route53** with different Routing Policies.
- Hands on experience on creating virtual private cloud (VPC) and subnets, route tables Internet gateway, NAT gateway, and subnet association.
- Hands on Experience with Guard duty, AWS Inspector & Creating AWSVPN.
- Experienced on Webservers such as Tomcat & Apache Server.
- Experienced in Creating users and setting up password authentication, disk mounting, date/time setup in Windows.
- Experienced in Creating LAMBDA Functions for EC2 instance automatic start/stop, automatic EBS volumes Backup.
- Hands on experience on configuring **cloud watch** monitoring tool such as pre-defined metrics custom Metrics (memory utilization, disk utilization, etc.) alerts.
- Experienced in Configuring to store **ELB** (Elastic Load Balancer) logs in **S3** Bucket.
- Worked on Cloud Migration for existing web applications by using AWS services.
- Experience with kinesis firehose and lambda to send cloud watch logs to Splunk.
- Hands on Experience on DMS service.
- Hands on Experience on SFTP service.
- Cloud-to-Cloud Migration using SMS service.
- Experienced in Creation of SMS Connector on On-Premises VM to connect to AWS and then creating Migration jobs to migrate.
- Experienced in Creating **RDS** instances MYSQL, PostgreSQL, Amazon Aurora.
- Also worked on migrating On-Premises MYSQL databases to AWS RDS- MYSQL Database.
- Exposure to Microsoft AZURE, Creating resources, Virtual machines.
- Hands on Experience in IAM, Monitoring, pub/sub, Cloud run, creating projects, Network services, Log based metrics, Cloud storage etc.

- Example: Ec2, VPC, Security.
- Exposure on **Docker** (Creating docker image, using ECS, elastic cluster, repository).
- Configured multiple **Docker files** as per the application requirement to run the service on the container start. All the images are saved to the **AWS Elastic Container Registry (ECR)**.
- Managed Docker orchestration and Docker containerization.
- Set up and manage **Docker** containers, running Java and node applications, and deploy into **Kubernetes Pods**.
- Used and implemented **Kubernetes (AKS)** to Deploy scale, load balance and manage pods in multiple namespaces.
- Deploying Terraform templates using Github Actions, Azure Devops, Jenkins.
- Experience maintaining CI environments with build automation tools like **Jenkins**, Bamboo and **GIT** and extensively used Jenkins to streamline CI/CD process, automated Master-Slave configurations using temporary slaves.
- Worked on CI/CD System with Jenkins on Kubernetes Environment for Build, Test and Deploy.
- Experience with **OpenShift** system integration, Infrastructure as a service and Cloud knowledge.
- Onboarding Nodes in **OpenShift** Cluster with a various business workloads.
- Performing the build activities using Jenkins and deployment with Helm/Terraform.
- Experienced with **Groovy** working knowledge.
- Oversee a team of personnel focused on technical issues and release and deployment.
- Built and managed, batch performance & batch jobs trend analysis reports using Power BI.
- Experienced working on CA7 Workload Automation, executing batch jobs and updating JIL as and when required.
- Experience on enabling/disabling MQ handlers using **IBM Data Power**, which is a messaging integration platform for few applications.
- Experienced on **IR360** for monitoring external/internal queues/queue managers that transforms different messages (XML/JSON) and there by act to move/put messages onto queues as required.
- Experienced on **TLS** certificate renewals using **VENAFI** and update **JKS** files in web/app servers and using **IIS** Manager.
- Experience on **IBM Urban Code Deploy** (uDeploy) tool for automated build and deployment for different applications from Development to Production environments.
- Supporting application dashboards that are built using Tableau.
- Addressing user issues (slowness/data related) within **Tableau** environment.
- Received numerous client appreciations for the quick analysis and solutions for very highly critical reports and issues.
- Worked on identifying, measuring, and reducing Toil.
- Working closely with Architecture, Development, Test, Security, and IT Services teams.
- Worked on **Splunk** logging to troubleshoot user issues.
- Experience on **AppViewX** monitoring/handling applications load balancing.
- Analytical skills to analyze/debug the problems in production environment and propose the solution.
- Production-support during warranty phase and transitioning and providing timely transition.
- Responsibility of handling any defects that are or can be encountered during the delivery life cycle and coming up with action items to eliminate their recurrence.
- Perform DML updates and SQL querying as per the business requirement and for issues to be debugged and resolved on database like **SQL Server/Oracle**.
- Prepared technical and training manuals for knowledge base.
- Provide data management support to users.
- Ensure all database programs meet company and performance requirements.
- Modify shell scripts and write Unix commands for different business requirement.
- Drive continual service improvement across Incident Management department and work with our partners to deliver improvements across people processes, and technology to increase stability and availability of IT services.
- Experience on **ITRS** Geneos monitoring applications/infrastructure alerts.
- Assist with management visibility into Service quality and process effectiveness with comprehensive reporting based on well-designed metrics.
- Identifying and debugging issues using several monitoring tools (App Dynamics/ Splunk/ Grafana).
- Involved in release and deployment related tasks during major and minor deployment on regular basis.
- Provide quick resolution for issues, which occur during business hours of wholesale banking which may affect sales, payments, and revenue.

Environment/Technologies: AWS (EC2, ELB, RDS, S3, CloudWatch, etc), Terraform, Github, Github Actions, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, uDeploy, IBM Data Power, Infrared IR 360, CA7 Workload Automation, Venafi, Splunk, Kafka, AppDynamics, SQL Server, Oracle DB 12c, Putty, AppViewX, IIS Manager, UNIX, Apache, Tomcat, Windows, XML, JSON, JIL, Enterprise Grafana, BigPanda, ITRS Geneos, PAC2000, Service Now, Confluence, JIRA, PowerBI.

Client: KLIQ Software Apr 2017 – Apr 2018

• Worked with teams of talented software engineers to define, build and maintain cloud infrastructure.

- Responsible for infrastructure monitoring and solutions.
- Identified gaps in market to spot opportunities to create value propositions.
- Responsible for Creating Infrastructure Using Terraform
- Identified gaps in market to spot opportunities to create value propositions.
- Managed use of various types of databases and configured, installed and upgraded new ones.

• Whole infrastructure used to be on premises; we have moved it into cloud completely. Played a key role during entire setup.

Client: Goldman Sachs (Contingent Worker)

Dec 2015 – Apr 2017

Project Name: Compliance

Compliance is a major part of any investment-banking firm. Sensitive and legacy applications and vary as part of data it is processing. There are 17 applications, which are part of our project, where we do production batch support, user support, maintenance, and enhancement.

Responsibilities:

- I worked as part of Compliance Information Services (CIS), Private Wealth Management, and Goldman Sachs Asset Management of Compliance Department at Goldman Sachs, which aims at generating sensitive trade reports and running surveillances, which are used, by regulatory bodies as well as internal trade surveillances.
- Resolve any queries raised by the user regarding any production issues.
- In my most recent role within the project, I worked extensively on Automating Routine tasks in Production with Python and Shell scripting to reduce manual intervention in Sensitive Production Environment.
- My responsibilities also included maintaining and monitoring scheduled jobs, infrastructure systems etc., and perform troubleshoot on processes and resolve all issues as a part of **Production support [L2&L3].**
- I worked on creation and management of Incidents based on ITIL guidelines and firm wide policies Acting as a technical expert for the entire team in terms of Unix and SQL.
- Acting as module lead for team of 5.
- Acting as the KM prime for the project.
- Building run book for removing dependencies of people.
- Training the new team members with the technical aspects of the project related to the Database.
- Implementing best practices like adhering to the coding standards for better code readability and maintaining traceability matrix to track the project status and check if all the requirements are met.

Rewards and Recognition

Received spot awards for outstanding performance.

Technologies: Sybase SQL, DB SQL, UNIX Tools: Aqua data,

Autosys Platform: LINUX OS

Client: Goldman Sachs (Contingent Worker)

Dec 2014 – Dec 2015

Project Name: Market Risk Technology

Market Risk Technology, a part of Goldman Sachs & Co., is responsible for designing, developing, and maintaining the suite of systems and applications for management, monitoring, and performing Risk Analysis for the firm. Market risk analysis involves usage of sophisticated Mathematical and Statistical models to produce various quantitative measures of risk numbers, such as Value-at-Risk (VaR), Extreme Stress Scenario Analysis and Risk Decomposition by market factors.

Responsibilities:

- 24*7 Level 1 & 2 Production monitoring.
- SLA compliance management (monitoring and reporting)
- Prioritization of strategic fixes to production issues / incidents.
- Maintenance of Autosys batches for 24*7 Live Production and QA Environments.
- Identification of Job failures, Responding to Automated System Generated Alerts.
- Resolving critical support issues through tools like Autosys, Procnosticator and AQUADATA studio.
- Tracking issues through JIRA.
- Investigation and Escalation (based on criticality of issues)
- Coordinating with Risk Analysts and various Market Risk teams to ensure on-time delivery of VaR.
- Documentation involving best practices, Support processes and Escalation Protocols.
- Tracking the frequent occurring incidents and identifying the root cause or escalation with development team and following till the resolution.

Environment / Technologies: Sybase SQL, DB SQL, UNIX Tools: AQUADATA, Autosys, Procnosticator Platform: LINUX OS

Employer: RS Solutions, MO, USA. Dec 2013 – Dec 2014

Responsibilities:

- Involving in Analysis, Design, and Development Testing and Production phases for the new requirements of the POMS Application.
- Analyzing functional requirements and writing technical design specifications for the new requirements.
- Developed JSP pages and Java Script for the applications.
- Involved in coding new features for the application.
- Designed and implemented data tables as per data model.
- Involved in Coding based on the spring framework.
- Wrote JUnit test cases for each requirement and tested the code as required.
- Involved in developing RESTful Web Services.
- Generated XSD's for Web Services consumers.
- Used HP Quality Center for defect tracking.
- Worked on AGILE methodology.
- Involved in **support for QA Team** while doing integration testing, regression testing, systems testing.

Environment: Java 1.6, J2EE 1.4, Spring 3.0, MQ Series, JDBC, XML, XSD, Web Services, Restful Web Services, ECLIPSE, Spring Source Tool Suite, Apache Tomcat Web Server, Informix, Log4J, UNIX, HP Quality Center 10.0, Load Runner 8.0, SVN, MYSQL, PLSQL, ORACLE, MS-Access, DB2, SYBASE.

Education

M.S., Electrical and Computer Engineering, Texas A&M University - Kingsville, USA. GPA - 3.2/4.0 [Aug 2012 – Dec 2013]

B.Tech., Electronics and Communication Engineering, JNTU, INDIA. Aggregate - 73% [Aug 2008 - Apr 2012]

Relevant Course Work: C, Java, Computer Organization, Computer Networks, and Tele-Communication Systems.

Skills

Tools: AWS (EC2, ELB, RDS, S3, CloudWatch, etc), Terraform, Github, Github Actions, Docker. Jenkins, UCD, Autosys, Power BI, App Dynamics, Splunk, Putty, Aqua Data Studio, IBM Data Power, Infrared IR 360, CA7 Workload Automation, Venafi, SQL Server, Oracle DB 12c, My SQL, Putty, AppViewX, IIS Manager, UNIX, SQL, Bash, Java, Kafka, C, C++, Shell Scripting, Apache, Tomcat, Windows, XML, JSON, JIL, Enterprise Grafana, BigPanda, ITRS Geneos, PAC2000, Service Now, Confluence, JIRA, MS Office, IBM DB2, Confluence, JIRA, SRS, iView, DB Visualizer, Eclipse IDE, Service Now.

OS: Unix/Linux, Windows.

Good verbal skills and ability to speak up for the team and for oneself. Ability to handle situations under pressure.